[music]
[音乐]
Hello and welcome to part 2
您好，欢迎来到第二部分
of lesson one. In this section we're going to look at the syntax that's used
第一课在本节中，我们将研究使用的语法
for
对于
Lambda expressions in Java. I mentioned
Java中的Lambda表达式。我提到
in the first part of this lesson that Lambda expressions are
在本课程的第一部分中，Lambda表达式是
like methods but they're not really methods, so let's
就像方法，但它们并不是真正的方法，所以让我们
go into a little more detail about why that is the case. The important thing
详细介绍为什么会这样。重要的事情
here
这里
is that a Lambda expression, although it represents
是Lambda表达式，尽管它表示
a method in terms of how we would use
关于我们将如何使用的方法
a particular interface, it's not associated
特定的接口，它没有关联
with a class. That's a very important thing we will come back to why that's
与一堂课。这是非常重要的事情，我们将回到为什么
really relevant as we go through the rest to this lesson.
与本课程的其余部分非常相关。
But the most important thing to get is that a Lambda expression
但是最重​​要的是Lambda表达式
represents method but is not associated with a class,
表示方法，但不与类相关联，
so we don't call it a method. What we call it
因此我们不称其为方法。我们称之为
is anonymous function. We can see here
是匿名函数。我们可以在这里看到
that the syntax of a Lambda expression
Lambda表达式的语法
is to use the Lambda operator. The Lambda operator is like a little arrow
是使用Lambda运算符。 Lambda运算符就像一个小箭头
formed by minus greater and a greater than symbol. On the left hand side
由负号“大于”和“大于”组成。在左手侧
of the Lambda operator are the parameters
Lambda运算符的参数是
that are past to the anonymous function, and in the case
在匿名功能中，
of Lambda expressions, if
Lambda表达式，如果
you have a single parameter then
你只有一个参数
you don't need to have the brackets. If you have no parameters
您不需要括号。如果没有参数
then you must have an empty set of brackets. If you have more than one
那么您必须有一组空括号。如果您有多个
parameter, then you must have the parameters separated by commas
参数，则必须用逗号分隔参数
with brackets around them exactly the same as you would
周围的括号与您的括号完全相同
in a method that you were calling. But in the case one parameter,
用您正在调用的方法。但是在一个参数的情况下，
the brackets are optional; you can put them but you don't have to.
括号是可选的；您可以放他们，但不必放。
The right hand side
右手边
all the Lambda operator is the body of the Lambda expression
所有Lambda运算符都是Lambda表达式的主体
and this is in essence the body of the method,
这本质上就是该方法的主体，
the body of the anonymous function.
匿名函数的主体。
Again if you have a single line
同样，如果您只有一行
Lambda expression then you don't need to include the braces.
Lambda表达式则不需要包含花括号。
Uou can do (they're optional) but you don't have to.
Uou可以做到（它们是可选的），但您不必这样做。
If you have multi-line Lambda expressions
如果您有多行Lambda表达式
then you will need braces and each line would need to be separated by semicolons
那么您将需要大括号，并且每行都需要用分号分隔
exactly the same way that we use Java. For
与我们使用Java的方式完全相同。对于
single line methods a single line bodies like
单线方法
some the examples you've already seen you don't need an explicit
您已经看到的一些示例不需要显式
return statement. Again if you want to you can put
返回声明。同样，如果您愿意，可以放
return statements in, but for
返回语句，但是
very simple Lambda expressions where you've only got one statement
非常简单的Lambda表达式，其中只有一个语句
you don't need to have an explicit return statement.
您不需要明确的return语句。
We will see some examples of that in a moment. That is the
稍后我们将看到一些示例。那就是
the essence a Lambda expression. The other thing
本质上是Lambda表达。另一件事
is that a Lambda expression, just like a method, can throw
就像方法一样，Lambda表达式可以抛出
exceptions. So the body of the Lambda expression
例外情况。所以Lambda表达式的主体
can have statements which will throw exceptions,
可以有会抛出异常的语句，
then these must be processed appropriately outside of the
那么这些必须在
Lambda expressions, and they must be caught and handled as they would be
Lambda表达式，必须按原样捕获和处理它们
with any other code.
与任何其他代码。
Here we have some examples all
这里我们有一些例子
Lambda expressions. The first one uses a
Lambda表达式。第一个使用
Lambda expression where we have no parameters
没有参数的Lambda表达式
so we have empty brackets. On the right hand side we have a very simple piece of code;
所以我们有空括号。在右侧，我们有一段非常简单的代码。
a single line, so we don’t need braces,
一行，所以我们不需要大括号，
we simply print out “hello Lambda”. The second one is more of a mathematical
我们只打印“ hello Lambda”。第二个是更多的数学
function. We have one
功能。我们有一个
parameter, x, so we don’t need to put brackets around that
参数x，因此我们不需要在该参数之间加上方括号
and then we’re simply returning the value x plus
然后我们只是返回值x加
10. The third example is a little more complicated,
10.第三个例子有点复杂，
what I have here is two parameters,
我这里有两个参数，
int x and int y, so again we must have the brackets around that
int x和int y，因此我们必须再次将其括在方括号中
and, in this case, I’ve chosen to use the braces,
在这种情况下，我选择使用花括号，
even though I’ve got a single line statement.
即使我只有一条语句。
One other thing that’s interesting, or relevant here is,
有趣或与此相关的另一件事是，
that if I do have a single line statement and I put braces round it
如果我确实有一条单行语句，并且将大括号括起来
I must terminate that single line with a semi-colon.
我必须用分号终止单行。
If I don’t have the braces, I don’t need the semi-colon.
如果没有牙套，则不需要分号。
If I do put the braces there I do need the semi-colon.
如果我确实把牙套放在那里，我确实需要用分号。
The next example takes two strings as parameters,
下一个示例将两个字符串作为参数，
string x and string y and returns the difference in length,
字符串x和y并返回长度的差，
so the compiler will figure out from what we’re doing that
所以编译器会从我们正在做的事情中找出来
obviously we’re passing in two strings and the
显然，我们传入了两个字符串，
difference in length will return an int or a long.
长度差将返回一个int或long。
Then we can have a slightly more complex
然后我们可以稍微复杂一点
body of the Lambda expression, where we’re passing in a single variable,
Lambda表达式的主体，我们在其中传递单个变量，
string x, again I’ve chosen to put the brackets around that I didn’t have to
字符串x，同样，我选择将括号放在不必要的位置
and we do need the braces and we have three statements,
我们确实需要大括号，并且我们有三个陈述，
listA dot add, listB dot remove and then we return the size
listA点添加，listB点删除，然后返回大小
of listB after having processed that, so we have an explicit return statement.
处理完listB之后，我们有一个明确的return语句。
Because it’s a multi-line
因为这是多行
Lambda body we must have an explicit return statement in that case.
在这种情况下，Lambda主体必须具有明确的return语句。
So these are all good examples of different Lambda expressions.
因此，这些都是不同Lambda表达式的良好示例。
We’ll see many more of these as we go through the rest of the course.
在本课程的其余部分中，我们将看到更多这些内容。
Now in terms of
现在来讲
what the compiler can do, it can actually now do
编译器可以执行的操作，现在实际上可以执行
better type inference. One of the things we did in JDK 8
更好的类型推断。我们在JDK 8中所做的一件事
was we rewrote a large part of the compiler
是我们重写了编译器的很大一部分
to handle type inference in a better way. What we have here is a situation where
以更好的方式处理类型推断。我们这里遇到的情况是
I've defined particular method so in this case it's called process
我已经定义了特定的方法，因此在这种情况下称为过程
has a generic type parameter, T, and
具有通用类型参数T和
what I’m going to do is have two parameters passed to that, one is going to be a list
我要做的是将两个参数传递给它，一个将是一个列表
of type T and the other is a comparator of type T.
类型T的比较器，另一个是类型T的比较器。
If I want to use that method then I could do something like this: I can create
如果我想使用该方法102 00：06：18,040-&gt; 00：06：21,190，则可以执行以下操作：我可以创建
list of type string and get it from
字符串类型列表，并从中获取
somewhere. When I want call process
某处。当我想要通话过程
I can call process, pass the list
我可以打电话给过程，通过清单
the one that I’ve retrieved form getList as my first parameter
我从getList检索到的第一个参数
and then I can use a Lambda expression
然后我可以使用Lambda表达式
to represent the comparator and we'll use the same one that we saw an example of on the
代表比较器，我们将使用与在上面看到的示例相同的比较器
previous slide where we're passing in two strings x and y
上一张幻灯片，我们传入两个字符串x和y
and we’re returning the difference in length of those strings.
然后我们返回这些字符串的长度差。
What that’s going to do is process something
要做的是处理一些东西
based on the difference in length of the strings.
基于字符串长度的差异。
The compiler is now smarter
编译器现在更智能
and that allows us to eliminate some of the work that we would normally have to do
这样我们就可以省去一些通常需要做的工作
do because, in this case, the compiler knows
这样做是因为在这种情况下，编译器知道
that list that we're passing into process
我们正在处理的那个清单
is of type string and from the definition of process
是字符串类型，来自流程定义
we know that the comparator must be of the same type
我们知道比较器必须是同一类型
as the list, because it uses the same type parameter.
作为列表，因为它使用相同的type参数。
Now what we can do is we can simply say in our
现在我们可以做的是，我们可以简单地说
process call pass in list and
处理呼叫传递列表和
when we define a Lambda expression we no longer have to explicitly state
当我们定义Lambda表达式时，我们不再需要明确声明
the types
类型
of x and y because the compiler knows that they must be strings
x和y的值，因为编译器知道它们必须是字符串
because the comparator must be of type string.
因为比较器必须是字符串类型。
In this case we don’t have to explicitly put the type in.
在这种情况下，我们不必显式地输入类型。
So we are completely free to put that in if you want to,
因此，如果您愿意的话，我们可以完全自由地输入它，
but if the compiler is able to infer the type for us, which it is in this case,
但是如果编译器能够为我们推断出类型，在这种情况下，
then we don’t actually have to do that.
那么我们实际上不必这样做。
This is good because it gives us less code to write,
这很好，因为它使我们编写的代码更少，
it gives us clearer syntax and it’s easier to understand what’s going on.
它为我们提供了更清晰的语法，并且更容易理解正在发生的事情。
Don't be alarmed by this, in no way are we introducing any form of
不要为此感到震惊，我们绝不会引入任何形式的
dynamic typing to Java.
动态键入Java。
X and Y are still very much statically typed as type string.
X和Y仍然非常静态地键入为类型字符串。
What we are giving you is more typing
我们给您的是更多打字
with less typing, which is a terrible pun I’m afraid.
打字少，恐怕这是一个可怕的双关语。
To summarise section two,
总结第二部分，
the syntax we’ve used for Lambda expressions
我们用于Lambda表达式的语法
is very straightforward, it’s very simple. All you have to remember
非常简单，非常简单。所有你要记住的
is that it's like a method and you have the Lambda
就像是一种方法，而您拥有Lambda
operator which is the arrow. The left hand side
运算符是箭头。左手边
of the Lambda operator represents the parameters that are being passed to the
Lambda运算符的代表正在传递给
method
方法
and the right hand side represents the body. if you have a single
右手边代表身体。如果你有一个
parameter the brackets around the parameter are optional.
参数参数周围的括号是可选的。
If you have a single statement for the body of the Lambda
如果您对Lambda的正文只有一个陈述
the braces around that are optional and if you do put braces around a single
大括号是可选的，如果您确实将大括号放在单个
statement
声明
you must put a semi-colon on the end of the line of code.
您必须在代码行的末尾加上分号。
Type inference
类型推断
means that we don't always have to explicitly state
意味着我们不必总是明确声明
the types of the parameters we’re using in a Lambda expression.
Lambda表达式中使用的参数类型。
Frequently the compiler is able to infer that for us
通常，编译器能够为我们推断
based on the type of the Lambda expression and therefore where it’s being used.
基于Lambda表达式的类型以及使用位置。
Java is very much still a strong,
Java仍然很强大，
statically typed language, so there's no worries about dynamic typing.
静态类型语言，因此无需担心动态类型。
And that is the end of
到此为止
part two of this lesson.
本课的第二部分。